Finding Aid for the Synanon Foundation Records LSC.0342
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Films
  - Children of Synanon: Composite Print, 1968; yrlsc_342_575_009; Lester, Howard; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:40) 600 feet; Film slightly warping and brittle. Made crackling noise as the film settled during unwinding. (Box 575, Case 9)
    Synanon archive #302. Can labeled: "Children of Synanon - Duplicate film of list no. 4" and "Projectionist: Note: Academy leader is part of the film, it is intended to be shown" Documentary on children living at Synanon and going to school. Playing the Game. Directed by Howard Lester with assistance from Chick Strand.
  - Synanon Commercial #1: Composite Reversal Print, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_575_010; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:02:05) 75 feet; Stressed, stretched, and torn perforations throughout film, almost every perf. Light scratching throughout on both sides. (Box 575, Case 10)
    Synanon archive #314. Label on reel: "#65 - Duplicate Synanon Commercial" Commercial for Synanon. Appears to mostly consist of still photographs of people at Synanon. End card: "Synanon Open House - Saturday 8:30 pm - San Francisco-Oakland"
  - Basic Training: Composite Print, circa 1975; yrlsc_342_576_001; 1 motion picture film (1 Super 8mm film; Duration: 00:07:30) 150 feet (Box 576, Case 1)
    Labeled: "Basic Training #13"
  - "Flag Ceremony at Candlestick Park": Reversal Print, circa 1976; yrlsc_342_576_002; 1 motion picture film (1 Super 8mm film; Duration: 00:03:45) 75 feet; Blue color cast to entire film. (Box 576, Case 2)
    In Kodachrome Duplicate Film box: "Flag ceremony at Candle-Stick Park in San Francisco - July 4, 1976 - 100 Syn People"
  - Unlabeled audio reel, undated; yrlsc_342_576_003; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape) (Box 576, Case 3)
  - "Musicians": Camera Original, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_576_004; 1 motion picture film (1 Super 8mm film; Duration: 00:02:30) 50 feet (Box 576, Case 4)
    Additional edge info: "EKco P 5/72"
  - "Children at Play": Camera Original, circa 1970; yrlsc_342_576_005; 1 motion picture film (1 8mm film; Duration: 00:02:05) 25 feet (Box 576, Case 5)
    Home movie. Original label: "B+W - Strangers - Children at Play - Swimming" and "[...] wife playing with the kids in ranch + program." and "She who must be IRU shooting - zoom!"
  - "Children at Play": Camera Original, undated; yrlsc_342_576_006; 1 motion picture film (1 8mm film; Duration: 00:04:10 50 feet; A few torn perfs at head. Emulsion scratch throughout. Rough film edges, but not many tears throughout. (Box 576, Case 6)
  - The Synanon Wedding Festival: Composite Print, 1972; yrlsc_342_576_007; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:40) 600 feet; Faded print with some scratching throughout. (Box 576, Case 7)
    Printed-in handwriting at head: "Synanon - MG - Synanon Wedding Festival - Color - Heads - Synanon Prod 'D- [cut off]" Printed-in handwriting at tail: "Synanon Wedding Festival" Festival for mass wedding held in Walker Creek Ranch on August 6, 1972, with 72 couples involved. Includes Chuck and Betty Dederich.
  - The Synanon People Ranch: Work Print, circa 1967-1970; yrlsc_342_576_008; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:40) 600 feet; RF foil cue tabs stuck on film throughout. Edge numbers printed onto emulsion side. Many different film stocks, single and double perf, edited together. Some sections more scratched than others. (Box 576, Case 8)
    Synanon archive #123. Silent work print of "The Synanon People Ranch." Black and white reversal cement-spliced together. Opening and ending titles included.
  - People Ranch, undated; yrlsc_342_576_009; 1 motion picture film (1 35mm film) (Box 576, Case 9)
  - Synanon Law Lecture #2: Dan Garrett: Fullcoat Mag (Reel 1 of 2), undated; yrlsc_342_576_010; 1 sound recordings (1 16mm full-coat mag; Duration: 00:27:46) 1000 feet (Box 576, Case 10)
    Synanon archive #178.
  - "Erotic 8mm Film c. 1965": Print, circa 1965; yrlsc_342_576_011; 1 motion picture film (1 8mm film; Duration: 00:20:50) 250 feet; Very low quality print with a lot of scratching on both base and emulsion. Many torn perfs at head. (Box 576, Case 11)
  - Synanon on Film - August 1972: Composite Reversal Print, yrlsc_342_576_012; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:14:35) 525 feet; Signs of projector trouble approx. 1/2 through reel: many torn perfs, tear in film previously repaired with splice time, scratches. Base scratch at this point as large squiggle across entire frame. (Box 576, Case 12)
    Part of internally distributed newsreels. Topics covered, separated by fades to black, include "Hot Time in the Hut," swimming, "Sherrifs and Deputies Move In" (in San Francisco), kayaking, and young women working on the ranch.
  - The Synanon Wedding Festival: Composite Reversal Print, 1972; yrlsc_342_576_013; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:14:35) 525 feet; Ektachrome reversal print, though not identified as such in edge information. Color is beautiful. Minor scratching on both sides, though mostly regular projector wear in sprocket area. Portion of missing frame previously repaired with splice tape, leaving gap in film (supported solely with tape). Series of cement splices and minor perf damage at head, suggesting projector damage previously mitigated. (Box 576, Case 13)
    Synanon archive #284. Printed-in handwriting at head: "Synanon Wedding Festival - Synanon - Prod. 'D-6' - 'C' Roll". Printed-in handwriting at tail: "Synanon 'Wedding Festival' CAP R-1B P/S - Tail Foot - Synanon 'B' D-6" Festival for mass wedding held in Walker Creek Ranch on August 6, 1972, with 72 couples involved. Includes Chuck and Betty Dederich.
  - Instant Guide to Synanon: Camera Original Outtakes, circa 1970-1973; yrlsc_342_578_001; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:40) 600 feet; Film slightly sticking to itself during unwinding. Great color. Reinforced one cement splice with tape. (Box 578, Case 1)
    Synanon archive #265. In Consolidated Film Industries box labeled "1 lite WP" on lid, "D-13 - 'Instant Guide' - Orig. - Out Takes - Live Action Roll #I + II - 1973" on side. Expansion of footage for most live-action scenes in "Instant Guide," including hand dialing in phone booth, Club Casa del Mar Synanon building, child care, car maintenance, monkey testing, San Francisco and Oakland Synanon buildings, scenes on Ranch.
  - Instant Guide to Synanon: Work Print Outtakes, circa 1972-1973; yrlsc_342_578_002; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:13:53) 500 feet; Reversal print (Box 578, Case 2)
    Synanon archive #264. Inside Consolidated Film Industries box labeled on side: "D-13 - Instant Guide - W.P. - Color & B&W Live Action - Trims & Out Takes - 1973" Mostly Ranch footage, some of which was used in "Instant Guide." Footage of San Francisco and Oakland Synanon buildings appears to be copied from yrlsc_342_578_001. At very head of film appears to be originally scratched segment for the halos that animate above Synanon members for one scene in "Instant Guide"
  - Instant Guide to Synanon: Work Print Outtakes, circa 1970-1973; yrlsc_342_578_003; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:19:26) 700 feet; Reversal print. Some minor perf tears throughout. Grease pencil marks on some splices. Some footage spliced in upside down. (Box 578, Case 3)
    Synanon archive #264. Inside Consolidated Film Industries box labeled on side: "D-13 - Instant Guide - W.P. - Color & B&W Live Action - Trims & Out Takes - 1973" Mostly live action footage from "Instant Guide," including shot of Detroit Synanon building. Some outtakes of animated segments at end of reel, including telephone image and question marks. Shots of slates including for some segments, especially animated ones. "
  - Synanon History Lecture #1: Outtakes, 1973; yrlsc_342_578_004; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:11:06) 400 feet; Tape splices all have some degree of overlapping film, at most one frame. Camera original, but only in terms of filming original video material. (Box 578, Case 4)
    Synanon archive #270a. Side of can labeled: "D-7 Synanon Lec. #1 [...] - Orig. - Outs - B&W - 1973" Video to film transfer of lecture on Synanon history at Synanon Research University in 1973. Footage is mostly of lecturer speaking, but footage is occasionally interrupted by video tracking errors, causing a hand to interject into the frame to recalibrate.
  - Synanon History Lecture #1: Outtakes, 1973; yrlsc_342_578_005; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:01:23) 50 feet; Tape splices all have some degree of overlapping film, at most one frame. Camera original, but only in terms of filming original video material. (Box 578, Case 5)
    Synanon archive #270b. Side of can labeled: "D-7 Synanon Lec. #1 [...] - Orig. - Outs - B&W - 1973" Video to film transfer of lecture on Synanon history at Synanon Research University in 1973. Footage is mostly of lecturer speaking, but footage is occasionally interrupted by video tracking errors, causing a hand to interject into the frame to recalibrate.
  - Camp Badger: Synanon in the Sierra: Title, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_578_006; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:02:05) 75 feet (Box 578, Case 6)
    Synanon archive #267. Inside metal can labeled on side: "Badger Title w/ & without Copywrite 1973 Pic Original" Consists only of blue title on black background: "Camp Badger: Synanon in the Sierra"
  - The Synanon Wedding Festival: Camera Original Outtakes, circa 1969-1972; yrlsc_342_578_007; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:20:50) 750 feet; Color quality poorer in 1969 Ektachrome segments (maybe slightly faded?). (Box 578, Case 7)
    Synanon archive #262. Inside Consolidated Film Industries box labeled on top: "D-6 - Wedding Festival - Orig. - Out Takes.- Pic. - 16MM - Color - 1973 - Roll #3" Same information on side of box. Silent footage from the Wedding Festival film. Contains significantly more material than included in finished film, especially of dancing in low light sequence at end of finished film.
  - The Synanon Wedding Festival: Camera Original Outtakes, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_578_008; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:06:56) 250 feet (Box 578, Case 8)
    Synanon archive #262. Inside Consolidated Film Industries box labeled on top: "D-6 - Wedding Festival - Orig. - Out Takes.- Pic. - 16MM - Color - 1973 - Roll #3" Same information on side of box. Wedding Festival footage and outtakes of titles.
  - Magic Flute: Composite Print, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_579_001; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:18:03) 650 feet; Film starts abruptly, may be missing footage at head. (Box 579, Case 1)
    Box labeled: "A-42 - Magic Flute Opera - Orig. - Video to Film - Pic. - 16mm - B+W - 1973" and "Synanon Original 22714 - Magic Flute - Video to Film - Opera"
  - Oakland Trip Break: Camera Original, circa 1967-1971; yrlsc_342_579_002; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:23) 590 feet; Torn perf toward head. (Box 579, Case 2)
    Synanon archive #187a. Box: "F 13 Trip Orig. & Workprint 187. Bag: ORIG DO NO PROJECT." Clapboard Credits - Title: Oakland Trip Break Editor: [...] Camera: Bolex I Date: 12-31-71 Cameraman: [...]
  - Oakland Trip Break: Work Print, circa 1971; yrlsc_342_579_003; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:23) 590 feet (Box 579, Case 3)
    Synanon archive #187b. Box: "F 13 Trip Orig. & Workprint 187."
  - The Synanon Wedding Festival: Fullcoat Mag Track 1, undated; yrlsc_342_579_004; 1 sound recordings (1 16mm full-coat mag; Duration: 00:16:40) 600 feet; The film exhibits extreme cupping, warping, and is fairly brittle. Deformation from hardened tape adhesive. Noticeable vinegar smell. (Box 579, Case 4)
    Box labeled: "D-6 Wedding Festival Orig. Master: Work Print + Mag. #1 Pic. + Track 16MM Color 1972" Leader labeled: "SYNANON WEDDING TRACK 1 HEAD / VOICE - KTVU COMMERCIAL TAIL (on additionally spliced on material)" Not the final sound mix - contains music & recorded live audio, does not have the narration. / Commercial for Synanon spliced to end.
  - The Synanon Wedding Festival: Work Print, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_579_005; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:40) 600 feet; The workprint has a number of splices using what looks like scotch tape, plus additional scotch tape reinforcements over cement splices. Too many to remove & redo at this time. / Editor note on leader towards tail of work print (record). Workprint is a dupe - edge codes noted are ektachrome EFB and Eastman Safety Film, unclear which one is original filmstock. First wind-through was very sticky (emulsion). (Box 579, Case 5)
    Box labeled: "D-6 Wedding Festival Orig. Master: Work Print + Mag. #1 Pic. + Track 16MM Color 1972" Leader labeled: "*HEAD* WEDDING PIC - W.P. / WEDDING D.6 WORKPRINT TAILS"
  - Charlie Hamer, circa 1971; yrlsc_342_579_006; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:26:23) 950 feet; Film warping and slightly brittle due to mag stripe. (Box 579, Case 6)
    Synanon archive #118a. Palmer Film Services paper bag: "Title: A21 Charlie - Property of: Synanon - Contents: Orig - EDJE# BC0200-BC1138 - L#15890". Consolidated Film Industries box: A-21-Charlie Hamer - Orig. - Pic. - 1972" On a ranch, taking care of animals. Two blonde children - boy and girl. Some scenes may be in Synanon Oakland. Starts with basketball footage similar, if not identical, to yrlsc_342_721_002.
  - Synanon on Film - August 1973: Voice Track Fullcoat Mag, yrlsc_342_579_007; 1 sound recordings (1 16mm full-coat mag; Duration: 00:13:53) 500 feet; Noticeable vinegar smell. Film severely warped as winding through. Original splice tape could stand to be replaced. (Box 579, Case 7)
    Synanon archive #121b. Box labeled: "A - Aug. S.O.F. Orig. Master: Voice + Music Track Track 16 MM 1973: 121" Boxed together with other full coat mag track.
  - Synanon on Film - August 1973: Music Track Fullcoat Mag, yrlsc_342_579_008; 1 sound recordings (1 16mm full-coat mag; Duration: 00:13:53) 500 feet; Noticeable vinegar smell. Film severely warped as winding through. Original splice tape could stand to be replaced. (Box 579, Case 8)
    Synanon archive #121a. Box labeled: "A - Aug. S.O.F. Orig. Master: Voice + Music Track Track 16 MM 1973: 121"
  - Upward Mobility: Work Print, undated; yrlsc_342_579_009; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film) (Box 579, Case 9)
  - Thickened Light Day: Mag Camera Original, circa 1971-1972; yrlsc_342_581_001; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:11:48) 425 feet; Mix of mag stripe sound (majority) and some silent double perf. All b&w. (Box 581, Case 1)
    Rehoused previously by UCLA staff with note added: "Thickened Light Day - Orig. - Pic. - 1972" added to lid. Footage of some kind of outdoor festival, with music, clowns, facepainting, and more. "Thickened Light" comes from an Emerson quote and appears to have been adopted by Synanon and used as the basis of an internal holiday, Thickened Light Day. "Thickened Light Demonstration" shown with elaborate diagrams on chalkboard. Synanon water tower indicates San Francisco.
  - The Synanon People Ranch: Composite Print, 1972; yrlsc_342_581_002; Hilberman, David, 1911-2007; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:15:58) 575 feet (Box 581, Case 2)
    Inside metal can with Palmer Film Services label: "Title: Synanon, The People Ranch (1972) / Property of: Synanon Foundation, Inc. [...] / Running time: 16:30 / Feet: 600 / Black and White / Sound" Also labeled "Archives Film Circulation Library" and "Orig # 40-10 Print (S) The People Ranch / Audit #27 and visual tapes." Note inside can indicating dates film was shown (with some signatures of who showed it). Promotional film depicting life in Synanon ranch.
  - The Synanon Wedding Festival: Composite Print, 1972; yrlsc_342_581_003; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:40) 600 feet; Very color faded. Big tear occurred during inspection, repaired with tape. Heavy, continuous scratches are worse at head and lighten up slightly throughout reel. Moldy film visible on original wind. (Box 581, Case 3)
    Label on can: "Synanon Foundation Inc. / [...] / Title: 1972 Synanon Wedding Festival / Number: 45-8 / Running Time: 16 min. / Feet: 606 / Color / Property of Synanon Foundation, Inc." Same label on metal reel. Other labels on can: "Audio/Visual #58 / Wedding Festival" and "45/8 Synanon Wedding Festival." Festival for mass wedding held in Walker Creek Ranch on August 6, 1972, with 72 couples involved. Includes Chuck and Betty Dederich.
  - The Mechanical Dolls: Camera Original, 1974; yrlsc_342_581_004; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:11:06) 400 feet; Appears to be camera original, but has been edited into narrative. (Box 581, Case 4)
    Synanon archive #152. Palmer Film Services label: "The Mechanical Dolls - Synanon House - [...] - about 8 min - 1974" Appears to be amateur film of dolls coming to life.
  - The Ids: Camera Original, 1972; yrlsc_342_581_005; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:05:33) 200 feet; Appears to be camera original film, but has been edited into narrative. (Box 581, Case 5)
    Synanon archive #153. "The Ids - [...] - 1972" Full film with titles about flirtatious people and their "ids" in a Synanon coffee shop. Produced by the Synanon School Department of Film.
  - "KGO-TV Synanon Wedding Festival": Mag Camera Original Outtakes, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_581_006; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:10:25) 375 feet; Significant deterioration to magnetic stripe soundtrack. Material has stuck to film layer underneath and peeled off, removing the soundtrack from its original position. Soundtrack subsequently likely unlistenable or very degraded. Film on original wind was stiff and bricklike, likely due to soundtrack fusing film layers together. Great reversal color with light base scratching. (Box 581, Case 6)
    Synanon archive #147. Inside metal can labeled: "Spliced Synanon Wedding 8-7-72 Outs - Projectable" and "Box - KGO-TV Outs Reel 2" Side of can labeled: "D-6 Wedding KGO Orig (RL-2) (Ceremony - Dance - Hoopla)" Wedding Festival footage, but appears to not be part of "Wedding Festival" film, due to being filmed by KGO-TV from San Francisco. Starts with wedding ceremony, but second half is mostly footage of "hoopla" dance party outside (in daylight) that followed the ceremony. "Synanon on Film" camerapeople visible in shots.
  - The Synanon Wedding Festival: Camera Original Outtakes, circa 1969-1972; yrlsc_342_581_007; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:09:01) 325 feet; Occasional light scratches. (Box 581, Case 7)
    Synanon archive #256. Inside can labeled: "D-6 W-9 Wedding - Orig Outs Pic - Never Workprinted 1972" Setting up festival area or other general preparation for "Wedding Festival." Meat preparation. Footage of dance during Wedding Festival. Many shots have color balance incorrect or cut off heads and/or feet, indicating likely reasons these are outtakes.
  - Oakland Trip Break: Camera Original, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_581_008; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:04:51) 175 feet; Sharp, beautifully exposed black and white. 24fps (Box 581, Case 8)
    Synanon archive #146. Side of can labeled: "A-10-Oakland Trip - Orig. - Pic. - 1972" Lid labeled: "Unreleased footage." Possibly refers to a "Trip" which functioned as extended Games over one weekend (48 hours). Footage shows people in white robes interacting with crowd of other people in street clothes. All celebrating, hugging, kissing, smiling, dancing to music. Panel of people also visible, many wearing different robes and Chuck Dederich in overalls.
  - Badger Trucking: Mag Camera Original, circa 1971; yrlsc_342_581_009; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:11:06) 400 feet; Slight warping perhaps due to mag stripe sound decomposition, though soundtrack appears to be in good shape. (Box 581, Case 9)
    Synanon archive #148. Inside Palmer Film Services paper bag labeled: "Property of: Synanon / Contents: Orig / EDJE # AC0000-AC0397 L# 15990" Inside metal can labeled on side: "A-26 - Badger Trucking - Orig - Pic 72" Synanon-branded truck loading equipment / supplies into Badger ranch, likely for construction. Tractor and other construction equipment. Synanon residents loading / unloading.
  - Badger Trucking: Work Print, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_581_010; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:10:25) 375 feet; Some tape reside at head from original tape label on roll. (Box 581, Case 10)
    Synanon archive #150. Side of can labeled: "A-26 Badger Trucking - W.P. - Pic. - 72 -" Palmer Film Services label on lid with no further information. Synanon-branded truck loading equipment / supplies into Badger ranch, likely for construction. Tractor and other construction equipment. Synanon residents loading / unloading. Silent copy of yrlsc_342_581_009.
  - Ground Breaking: Work Print, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_581_011; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:03:28) 125 feet (Box 581, Case 11)
    Synanon archive #151. Side of can labeled: "A-40 - Ground Breaking - W.P. - Pic - 1972" Lid of can labeled with information for "Legal Suit," possibly indicating can was reused from something related to yrlsc_342_722_010. Construction equipment on ranch. Digging. Men in overalls. Likely related, if not copy of, to yrlsc_342_582_004. Same "A-24 Girl Slobs" at tail.
  - The Synanon People Ranch: Outtakes, circa 1971; yrlsc_342_581_012; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:05:33) 200 feet; Light scratching throughout, though some visible scratches are printed-in, not on the film itself. Redox blemishes throughout from original tape. (Box 581, Case 12)
    Synanon archive 257a. Inside can labeled: "D-5 A-People Ranch - Orig. - Outs - Pic. - 1972" On ranch, group with motorcycles outside. Dederich with group, talking and gesturing. People eating intercut with horses and other animals eating. Classroom scenes, chalkboard.
  - Lighting With Quartz: Composite Reversal Print, 1970; yrlsc_342_581_013; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:09:43) 350 feet; Uncut film. Film is black and white printed on color stock that has now slightly faded. (Box 581, Case 13)
    Can labeled: "0 2 Lighting With Quartz" Reel labeled: "Lighting with Quartz 1970" SMPTE countdown at head. Animated opening title: "Lightweight Lighting / 30 Jun 70" Credits end with line "We're all goin' to jail." Men in U.S. Army uniforms (those identified in the credits) demonstrating using Lowell Quartz 2 Kit for lighting a sound stage for filming. Appears to be instructional film and includes close-ups on light equipment and light meter.
  - Children's Summer Camp: Camera Original, circa 1971-1972; yrlsc_342_582_001; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:25:00) 900 feet (Box 582, Case 1)
    01a: "A33 Children's Summer Camp." "Synanon - W.O. #13696 - 'Kids' Original" 01b: A33 Kids original (was workprinted 1st).
  - Synanon's 10th Anniversary: Print, circa 1968; yrlsc_342_582_002; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:05:33) 200 feet; Uncut film. Printed-in edge info "Kodak N 82 Safety Film" with 1965 date code (square circle). (Box 582, Case 2)
    Printed-in handwriting at head: "10th Anniversary - #29 - Synanon - Head (PFT)." Same info at tail.
  - Tomales Construction: Work Print, circa 1973; yrlsc_342_582_003; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:01:23) 50 feet; Black and white images, but perhaps printed onto color film stock? Reversal. Only scratches are sprocket wear. (Box 582, Case 3)
    Synanon archive #183. "E-16 Tomales Construction - Workprint - Pic - 1973" Cows in shadow or out of focus, filmed from barn. Likely filmed in Tomales Bay, Marin County where Synanon owned land and built ranches.